Shresth Shukla

Data Analyst/Scientist

■ thisisshresth@gmail.com• 9354841168• Delhi NCRIn LinkedIn• UselessAI.in

Github ● Medium

PROFILE

Experienced and curious AI enthusiast with a background in solving problems using data and AI technologies. Began my career in **technical content writing** \mathscr{O} and developed a passion for technology, AI development and research. Now focused on addressing larger challenges with technology at hand and humans at the center. Currently helping one of the biggest climate organizations with Data Engineering and AI implementation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Analyst - Data and AI

Ernst & Young (EY) India

08/2023 – present Delhi, India

- Involved in the development of 10+ **GenAI** solutions, gaining expertise in building various **RAG** architectures using Azure OpenAI across multiple sectors. Read alot of papers. I write *⊗* too:)
- Developed a computer vision solution using YOLO, SAM and OpenCV, gaining expertise in model training, image and video analytics, and image classification and segmentation.
- Working on **Microsoft Fabric** and **Azure** to implement data pipelines, perform data transformation and data preparation using **PySpark**, leveraging Azure AI and Copilot capabilities as part of the Data and AI team for a project. Collaborating with PowerBI team to turn complex KPIs into visual content.
- Working on Fabric Data Factory, Notebooks, Deployment Pipelines, managing overall project development on Microsoft Fabric.
- Managed 8+ people to work collaboratively on Data and AI projects/usecases. Involved in business decision-making for various Data & AI solutions and client engagement.
- Built an automatic voice-based form-filling solution-**Sevak**, that can understand input in all Indian languages and fill the form in English automatically, without any human intervention.

Content Writing and Storytelling

Classplus

Written content for top executives of the company including CEO, CFO, and CMO
of the company. Gained experience of crafting customer stories for building brand
awareness. Utilized python to automatically scrape linkedin stats and turn it into
report.

12/2022 – 05/2023 Noida, India

EDUCATION

M.Tech in Software Systems

BITS Pilani (Hyderabad Campus)

 Gaining knowledge and experience by working in technology, attending classes, and taking exams. Won a GenAI competition hosted at the BITS Hyderabad campus. 10/2023 – present

Bsc. Maths Hons 11/2020 - 05/2023

Delhi University (ARSD)

• Explored mathematics in and out, made friends, went on trips, and did whatever suited best at the time. Scored 8.5+ CGPA:)

PROJECTS

Multi Speaker Context Aware Podcast Generation ∅

Turned my medium blogs into a mutiple speaker and context aware podcast using LanceDB, ElevenLabs/Smallest and Gemini.

SPYC &

Learnt about LanceDB Cloud while working on a competitor analysis project using vector search and AI. Built a small agent that can look up different tables depending on the question to search for context.

SKILLS

Generative AI (GenAI)

Deep Learning, Langchain, RAG (using Gemini and Azure OpenAI), **Conversational AI** (Whisper & **Bhashini**), PyTorch (as required), Transformers, Fine Tuning, Pydantic, Agentic AI, MCP, FastAPI

Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning (AI-

Python, PySpark, Pandas & Numpy, Machine Learning(scikit-learn and algorithms), Computer Vision (CV), Object Detection (YOLO & ViT), Image Classification and Segmentation (SAM)

Microsoft Fabric

Fabric Data Factory(**DF**) ∅, Data & Deployment Pipelines, Data Transformation (PySpark & SQL), Azure AI Services, Workflow Automation (Logic Apps), Data Warehouse, Medallion Architecture

Product and Business Communication

Product Management and Analytics, Better **Prompting**, Business and Client Meetings, Leading Presentations, Team Management, Leadership, Content Writing, Analytical Thinking

REWARDS

Client Extraordinaire 01/11/2024

- Received a client extraordinaire award for excelling in client deliverables and contributing significantly to the Data and AI project for international client. Gained valuable experience in client project management and delivery.
- Helped client migrate and manage their overall data system on Microsoft Fabric.

Edu-Forge Competition

16/04/2024 BITS Pilani

• Attended the ICONWIL Conference, competed with 60+ developers and data scientists from companies like IBM, Accenture, Cognizant, and TCS, and secured **1st prize** for a GenAI solution on Work-Integrated Learning.

STOA RAIL

STOA

- Collaborated with 5 strangers on a train journey to ideate a business plan during a **30-hour trip** from Delhi to Bangalore. Secured **3rd rank** among 55+ candidates.
- Additionally, ranked in top 3 in multiple inter-college competitions, including business case studies and idea pitching. Won 1st prize by Enactus, ARSD.

CERTIFICATES

EY Badges

Received 5 Bronze and Bronze **Learning Badges** *⊘* for Data Integration, AI Engineering, Data Science and Government and Public Sector.

DBMS and SQL

Earned mutiple MOOC's certificates & related to Database Management, SOL (intermediate and advanced), Data Science and Machine Learning.

Kaggle Learnings

Dedicated weekends to gaining hands-on AI-ML experience through Kaggle, earning multiple certification credentials upon course completion.

INTERESTS

Teaching — I'm teaching mathematics to kids since I was in grade 8th. Now aligned it towards capacity building projects in AI. | **Chess** — 1300 elo. I play it whenever I get time or want to refresh my mind. | **Writing** *⊗* — I love writing about what I learn and try to make technical concept simpler for non tech people. These days, I write and publish blogs at UselessAI.in ∂